Mob Psycho
Namu
Amida
Butsu
Believe it or not, the world is
filled with strange phenomena
（ナレーション）
世の中には いまだに
科学では解明できない怪奇現象が
that science is yet to explain.
確かに存在する
And when people come face to face with them,
人々は それらと出くわしたとき
they are helplessly thrown
into the dark depths of fear.
なすすべもなく ただ
恐怖の闇に突き落とされてしまう
But there are those who fight every day
そんな混沌(こんとん)とした闇に
ひと筋の光をさすべく
to shine a ray of hope
into that chaotic darkness.
日々 戦い続ける者たちがいた
People call them...
人は彼らを こう呼んだ
Psychics
“霊能力者”と
Psychics.
I, Reigen Arataka, shall accept this job!
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
その依頼
この霊幻新隆が引き受けた！
Reigen
Arataka
Really? Thank you so much!
（花子(はなこ)）
ホントですか？
ありがとうございます！
どこに相談しても相手にされなくて
困ってたんです
I was at a complete loss because
no one else would take me seriously.
Client: Hanako
I see, I see.
（霊幻）
ああ… はいはい
で 報酬の話なんですけど
どのコースで除霊しましょう？
As for my fees, it depends on
which exorcism course you pick.
Course?
（花子）
コース？
Executing the Exorcism!!
We will do our best to reduce the spirit possessing you
Option A — Trial Course
A Mere 2,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside Offer Period: 3,980 yen.
Option A, the trial course, gets you 20%,
（霊幻）
お試しＡコースですと
20パーセント
Option B — Serious Course
A Mere 5,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside of Offer Period: 8980 yen
Option B, the serious course, gets you 50%,
真面目Ｂコースだと
50パーセント
Recommended
Option C — All-Out Course
A Mere 12,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside of Offer Period: 19880 yen
Refer us to a friend now and
get an extra 5% reduction!!
Also get an add-on exorcism for 20% off!!
and Option C, the all-out course,
gets you a 99%...
本気のＣコースだと
99パーセント
霊を削減することを お約束します
reduction in spirit, guaranteed!
Reduction?
（花子）
削減？
Well, spirits are sort of
like carbon dioxide.
霊っていうのは
二酸化炭素的な あれですから
ええっ そうなんですか？
They are?
Yes, well... that's the kind of
space they occupy,
ええ まあ…
そんなニュアンスの存在っていうか
Spirits and Such
Consultation Office
so it's a bit hard to
completely get rid of one.
（霊幻）
だから 完全に消すっていうのは
ちょっと困難なんですけど…
ですが 心配ご無用！
また出たら…
But have no fear.
If it appears again,
I'll take care of it for 20% off!
２割引きで請け負いますから！
Oh, Reigen-sensei!
ああ～ 霊幻先生！
Hold on a second!
（太郎(たろう)）
ちょっと待った～！
Hm? Who might you be?
ん？ 何だね 君は！
This is my boyfriend, Taro.
（花子）
恋人の太郎です 先生
Ah, what a benevolent fellow!
ほ～う 奇特な方だ
What's that supposed to mean?!
Boyfriend: Taro
どういう意味だ！
あ… いや そんなことより
Er, that aside...
Listen up, you!
あんた！
いかにも うさんくさいぞ
This is super shady!
（花子）
ああ…
Hanako, you should really rethink this.
花子 考え直したほうがいいぜ
"This is super shady"?!
（霊幻）
うさんくさいだと？
ふん！ まあ そうなるよな
I guess I can't blame you
for feeling that way.
I mean, who would believe a stupid story
like having nightmares about ghosts?
幽霊にうなされるなんてアホな話
いきなり されてもなあ…
I wasn't talking about her!
（太郎）
いや 彼女じゃなくて
I was saying that I can't trust you!
あんたが信用できないって
言ってんの！
Well, just leave it to me.
（霊幻）
まあ 任せなさい！
If I exorcise the spirit,
俺が ちゃんと除霊すれば
花子さんの顔も
I'm sure Hanako-san's face
will return to normal, too.
きっと 元どおりになるはずだ
There's nothing wrong with her face!
別に顔で悩んでねえよ！
I see.
（霊幻）
なるほど 先週 肝試しをしてから
毎晩 夢を見るようになったと
So you've been having those dreams ever
since you did a test of courage last week.
Yes. They're so scary and creepy.
（花子）
はい もう怖いし 気味が悪いし…
Ah, Reigen-sensei,
it's that building over there!
あっ 霊幻先生 あの建物です
What an incredible aura!
ものすごい霊気を感じる～！
This is gonna be the first
big one I've had in a while!
こいつは 久々の大物だああ～！
Sensei, it's this building over here.
（花子）先生 こっちです…
（霊幻）はっ！
Wait, you just pointed at
the wrong building, didn't you?
あれ？ 今 間違えて…
（霊幻）
いや ハハハハッ！
Huh? Ah, so it's that one!
えっ？ ああ そっちか～
There was such an immense aura
emanating from over there, too.
そっちからも すごい霊気
ビシビシ来てたんだけど
こりゃまた 霊違いでしたな～
I guess I got the wrong spirit!
世の中 悪霊なんか
クソのほど いますからね～
There are way too many evil spirits
in this world, you know?
Ah, I see.
ええ そうなんですか？
いやいや そんな幽霊が
どこにでもいるわけが…
Please. There's no way
there are ghosts everywhere—
Oh, no!
（霊幻）
いやいや～！
That man who just
walked past you, Taro-san...
今 太郎さんの横を通り過ぎた男！
What?
What a close shave.
That was an evil spirit, too.
危なかった… 今のは悪霊ですよ
（２人）
えっ！
あっ あああ…
（太郎）
うっ うっ うわ…
The Buttchin Goblin.
（霊幻）
妖怪ケツあご
What are you, eight?!
（太郎）
小学生か お前は！
Hey, Taro, that's rude!
ちょっと 太郎！ 失礼よ
What? He's the one being rude
to that random guy.
ええ？ 失礼なのは こいつだろ？
あの おっさんに対して…
Now, now, Hanako-san.
（霊幻）
まあまあ 花子さん！
There are always people like him.
こういう人もいる… ということで
Anyway, shall we go?
（霊幻）
さっ 行きましょうか
This bastard...
（太郎）
こいつ～！
They say this place is haunted by the
spirit of a man who saw a cockroach
（花子）
この土地は…
昔ゴキブリに驚いてジャンプしたら
天井に頭が刺さって死んだ男の
and jumped so high, his head went
through the ceiling and he died.
霊が出るといわれてるんです
ううう…
I don't know how
you actually believe that.
お前 よく信じるよな
I see.
なるほど
ここは そういうことか…
So that's what is going on here...
What? He suddenly looks all serious.
（太郎）
何だ？ 急にマジな顔に！
まさか… 本当に？
Could there really be...
If worst comes to worst,
even I might not be able to handle it!
事態によっては
私でも手に負えない可能性がある！
This is too dangerous!
（霊幻）
危険すぎる！
（２人）
ううう…
Cockroaches are terrifying!
（霊幻）
ゴキブリ 怖(こえ)え～！
（太郎）
えっ？
Huh?
うわ～
こいつ 絶対 霊能力者じゃねえ！
There's no way this guy is a psychic!
He's a total fake!
確実に 偽者だ～！
あっ…
（悪霊）
お前の夢にも出てやろうか？
Want me to haunt your dreams, too?
A ghost!
出た～！
Evil Spirit:
Ceiling Crasher
Want me to crash you through
the ceiling with my curse?
（天井破(てんじょうやぶ)り）
俺様の呪いで
天井を突き破ってやろうか？
ぎゃあ～！ 夢で
頭突きしてくる人と おんなじよ～
That's the same guy who keeps
headbutting me in my dreams!
きゃ～！
I can't believe he actually appeared.
（霊幻）
まさか マジで出るとは…
I've got this!
任せろ！
Salt Splash!
ソルトスプラ～ッシュ！
Salt Splash
This is Reigen's special move
（ナレーション）
食塩を激しく まき散らす
霊幻の必殺技である
where he violently throws
table salt everywhere.
This is just table salt
you can buy in stores.
スーパーで売ってる食塩じゃねえか
清めた塩じゃねえと効かねえよ
It has to be purified salt,
or it won't work.
Hakata Salt
Impossible...
（霊幻）
バカな…
Did I only imagine that spirits
are weak against salt?
霊が塩に弱いというのは
俺の思い込みだったのか…
フッ まあ
塩で溶けないんじゃ しかたない
Well, if salt won't melt it, I guess
I'll have to call my ultimate weapon.
最終兵器を呼ぶか！
Oh, Mob?
あっ モブ？
悪いけど すぐ来てくれるか？
Sorry, but could you come by?
No, seriously.
あっ いや マジで マジで
悪霊いるんだって！
There's an evil spirit.
The client and the evil spirit
are both waiting,
（霊幻）
お客さんと悪霊も
もう待ってるから 早めにな！
so hurry up, okay?
Thanks.
じゃ 頼む
（花子と太郎）
えっ…
Ah, Mob.
（霊幻）
おお モブ！ 待ってたぞ
We were waiting for you.
（天井破り）
ん？
ふ～ん…
ヘッ！ 食塩の次は中学生か？
Hmph.
So after the salt,
you're using a middle schooler?
Quit looking down on—
バカにするのも…
おお～ うわああ～！
He is Kageyama Shigeo,
also known as Mob.
（ナレーション）
彼の名は影山茂夫(かげやましげお)　通称“モブ”
Kageyama
Shigeo
Mob
He's an actual psychic,
本物の超能力者であり
霊幻新隆の弟子である
Reigen Arataka's student,
and the protagonist of this story.
そして この物語の主人公である！
Master, I asked you not to
summon me on such short notice.
（モブ）
師匠 いきなり呼び出すの
やめてくださいって…
～
Mob Psycho
Spirits and Such
Consultation Office
Man, you're a lifesaver.
（霊幻）
いや～ 助かったぜ
まさか 本当に悪霊が出るとはな
I never thought that an evil spirit
would actually show up.
Here. Your pay for the day.
ほれ 今日のバイト代だ
Oh, thank you.
（モブ）
ああ どうも
That one today was a lower-level spirit,
今日のは低級なヤツだったから
半分でも十分なんだけどな
so I really shouldn't be
paying you more than half.
まあ サービスだ
ちゃんと時給分やるよ！
But I'll give you your hourly pay.
Think of it as a bonus.
（モブ）
はあ…
Right...
（霊幻）
ん… 何だ？ 不満なのか？
What? Do you have a problem with that?
Oh, no.
あっ いえ… ただ さっきの
本当に低級なヤツでしたよ？
But the spirit back there
really was a lower-level spirit.
（モブ）
あれくらいなら…
It was so weak, you...
バ… バカ！ お前…
Y-You idiot!
When you get to my level,
you get so strong,
俺くらいになると強すぎて
簡単な除霊作業だと
you end up melting everyone around you
during a simple exorcism.
周りの人まで溶かしちゃうの～！
That's why I ask you to take
care of the weaker ones.
だから 弱いのは お前に頼むんだよ
Really?
本当ですか？ “溶ける”の意味も
よく分かりませんし…
I'm also not quite sure what
you mean by "melt," either...
Mob, you idiot!
（霊幻）
バカ！ モブ お前
それは修行が足りないからだよ
That's because you lack training!
The New Star of the 21st Century
Reigen Arataka
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
You need to learn everything
you can from me, your master!
きっちり学べよ～
この師匠からな！
Your powers are meant to be used.
Not doing so would be a waste.
お前の“力”は
使わねえと もったいないんだ
俺の手伝いは 人助けにつながるし
修行になるし 一石二鳥だろうが
Working for me lets you help others,
while also being training for you.
You're killing two birds with one stone!
However, if you misuse
a power that's all too great,
だが 強大すぎる“力”は
使い方を誤れば 己の身を滅ぼす
you will only destroy yourself.
That's why I'm teaching you how to control
your powers so they don't go berserk.
だから 暴走しないよう
“力”のコントロールのしかたを
俺が教えてやってるんだよ
That's why I'm teaching you how to control
your powers so they don't go berserk.
You promised me, didn't you?
（霊幻）
約束しただろ？
That you wouldn't use your psychic
powers against other people.
“人に向けて
超能力は使わない”って
Progress Toward
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 22%
（モブ）
あ～
ああ…
Ah...
There you go again, bending spoons.
（モブの母）
ま～た この子はスプーン曲げて！
いいかげん 直しなさいよ その癖！
You really need to drop that habit.
（モブの父）
いいじゃないか
茂夫も思春期なんだ
Oh, come now.
Shigeo's going through puberty.
Let him bend some spoons.
スプーンくらい 曲げさせてやれよ
なあ？
Right?
Heh, sorry.
（モブ）
エヘッ 失敬…
また そうやって甘やかして！
茂(しげ)も少しは 律(りつ)を見習いなさいよ？
And there you go, spoiling him again.
You need to learn from Ritsu, Shige.
He got another perfect score
on his quiz today.
今日も 小テストで
満点とったんだから！
（影山 律(かげやま　りつ)）
あんなの 誰でも できるよ
Anyone can do that, Mom.
If there's anything troubling you,
let me know, Nii-san.
何か 悩みがあるなら言ってよ
兄さん
いつでも 相談に乗るから
I'll be there to listen any time.
Kageyama Ritsu
Right. Thanks, Ritsu.
うん ありがとう 律
And now you're spoiling him, too, Ritsu.
もう 律まで甘やかして…
次 曲げたら
茂のお小遣いで買うからね！
The next one you bend gets replaced
using your allowance, you hear?
（モブ）
えっ！
Huh?
ごめん 兄さん
それは僕にも どうにもできないや
Sorry, Nii-san.
There's nothing I can do about that.
（モブの父）
ハッハッハッハ
こいつは困ったなあ？ 茂夫
Now you're in a real pickle, Shigeo.
Seasoning City, Salt Middle School
Morning!
（チャイム）
（男子生徒）おはよう～
Salt Middle School
あっ…
Right?
Good morning, Tsubomi!
（女子生徒）
ツボミ おはよう
（ツボミ）
おはよう～
Morning!
What a beautiful day!
いい天気だね！
Oh, yeah. On TV yesterday...
（ツボミ）
あっ そういえば 昨日テレビでね…
What?
Tsubomi-chan's as cute as ever today...
（モブ）
今日もかわいいな… ツボミちゃん
Okay, so, what would be the answer here?
（教師）
はい すると…
ここの答えは どうなる？
Let's go with Kageyama.
じゃあ… 影山
（モブ）
あっ はい！
Y-Yes, sir...
Arithmetic I
あああ… 分かりません
I have no idea.
If you can't solve this, that'd mean
the only thing you know is addition.
（教師）
これが分からんと
もう 足し算しか残ってないぞ？
はあ…
You were asleep, weren't you?
寝てただろ？ お前
（生徒たち）アハハハ…
（教師）もういい！ 座ってろ
Forget it. Sit down.
（モブ）
ハア…
There it goes!
（男子生徒）
行ったぞ～！
This way!
うっ… うう～
Pass, pass, pass!
ああ… たあ～
ハア ハア… ああ うわ～
Go, go!
Stop 'em!
Pass, pass!
Go!
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
Reigen Arataka
（モブ）はい
Hello?
Ah, Mob?
（霊幻）
ああ モブ？
Sorry to call you two days in a row,
昨日の今日で悪いけどな
すぐに駅まで来てくれるか？
but could you come down
to the station right now?
The station?
駅… ですか？
Yeah.
ああ 今日の仕事は デケえぞ
Today's job is a big one.
Oh. All right.
ああ… 分かりました
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 25%
Today's job is from
a local neighborhood council.
（霊幻）
今回の依頼は 地元の自治会からだ
The location is Honeido Tunnel
along the old highway.
場所は
旧街道にある 骨井戸(ほねいど)トンネル
It's a famous haunted place.
Famous Haunted Spot
Terror
Haunted
Ghost
Tunnel
Eek!           Aah!
The location is the old Seasoning Highway
Honeido Tunnel
（霊幻）
有名な心霊スポットだ
The tunnel's always had some shady stories,
もともと いわくつきのトンネルで
閉鎖されて何年もたつが
and even though it's been closed for years,
the bad rumors just won't go away.
いまだに悪いウワサは絶えない
Also, a number of college students
and bloggers have gone there
肝試しに来た大学生やらブロガーが
行方不明になったって事件が
to do a test of courage
and gone missing.
何件も起こってる
And this is the ringer.
極め付けは これだ！
Honeido Tunnel Group Accident
A huge group accident?
（モブ）
集団走行中の事故… ですか？
（霊幻）
ああ 30年前の話だがな
Yeah, though it happened thirty years ago.
一度に
20人以上が亡くなったらしい
Apparently, more than
twenty people died at once.
このトンネルには
The hatred of all those people
must be swirling around this tunnel.
それだけの怨念が
渦巻いてるってわけだ
（モブ）
はあ…
（霊幻）ああっ…
Stay on your toes, Mob.
There's no telling what might happen.
（霊幻）
不測の事態に備えて
集中しとけよ モブ！
Oh, right.
（モブ）
ああ… はい
Honeido Tunnel
This is it.
（霊幻）
ここか…
Well, let's take a look.
どれ いっちょ見てやるか！
霊能界の新星 この霊幻新隆が
きれいに掃除してやろう
I, Reigen Arataka, the new star
of the paranormal world,
shall clean this place up.
We're going to exorcise every
last one of them, Mob.
１匹 残らず 除霊するぞ モブ！
Hey, my student!
（霊幻）
おい そこの弟子～！
What are you doing, Mob?
何やってんだ？ モブ
お前も来るんだよ！
You're coming, too!
It'll be bad if the sun goes down.
（霊幻）
日が暮れたら やっかいだ
Mob, are you listening?
モブ？ 聞いてんのか！
（モブ）
あ…
I'm gonna go melt down a
big one, so follow me!
デケえの溶かしに行くから
ついてこい！ なっ？
Got it?
分かりました
All right. You seemed to have
everything under control,
余裕に見えたので
手伝いは いらないのかと…
so I didn't think that you'd need my help.
You idiot! Who do you think is
going to exorcise—Ahem.
バカ！ 誰が除霊… ゴホンッ
I mean, this really is nothing for me,
まっ 余裕だけども！
勉強だと思って ついてこい！
but follow me so you can learn something.
（モブ）
師匠は さすがですね
You're truly amazing, Master.
Hm?
あっ？
This tunnel seems pretty dangerous.
あのトンネル 結構ヤバそうですよ
（霊幻）
えっ？
I can sense the presence of a very
powerful spirit further down.
（モブ）
奥の方から 強い霊の気配を
ピリピリと感じます
Usually, haunted spots end up being fake,
心霊スポットって
デマ情報も多いじゃないですか？
but this is definitely the real deal.
けど 今回は本物でしたね
If a normal person happened to
anger the spirit in here...
もし 一般人が
あの中の霊を怒らせたら…
If they angered it...?
（霊幻）
怒らせたら？
They probably wouldn't
make it out in one piece.
（モブ）
無事じゃ済まないと思いますね！
Of course not.
当たり前だ
That's why we're going to exorcise it.
だから
俺たちで除霊するんだろうが！
All right, here we go!
（霊幻）
よ～し 行くぞ！
I'll go first.
俺が前を行く
お前は後ろから
適当にサポート 任せるぞ！
I'm counting on you to support me
however you can from behind.
はい！
Right.
It's a bit chilly.
ひんやり 涼しいな…
Yes.
そうですね
懐中電灯 忘れたなあ
We forgot to bring flashlights.
Master, don't you feel something?
（モブ）
師匠 何か感じませんか？
Hm?
（霊幻）
ん？ そういや かなり湿気があるな
Well, it is pretty humid in here...
No, I'm talking about auras.
（モブ）
いや 霊気の話ですよ
Oh, right, that.
（霊幻）
おお～ そっちな！
ああ そうだな…
Well, my nose is a bid sduffy doday.
今日は鼻が詰まってるからな～
鼻詰まりが関係あるんですか？
Does that have anything to do with this?
俺くらいになるとな…
When you get to my level, it does.
Do you feel anything?
お前は 何か感じるか？
感じるなんてもんじゃないですよ
Feel would be an understatement.
There are twelve...
12… 18…
いや それ以上 いますね
Eighteen...
No...
Even more right nearby.
すぐ近くに… あっ
Ah!
（霊幻）ひっ…
（モブ）完全に囲まれましたね
Looks like we've been completely surrounded.
襲ってきますよ
They're going to attack us now.
All right!
（霊幻）
よしっ 雑魚は任せた
やれ！ モブ！
I'll leave the small fry to you.
Go, Mob!
Man, that's a lot of noise.
They're really strong, huh?
いや～
そんな激しい音がするほどか～
う～ん もし一般人だったら
危なかったのかな～？
Hmm... If we were normal people,
we might have been in danger.
Well, I'm sure that took care of all of them.
まあな どうせ あれで全滅だろう
今回も 楽… うう～！
Another piece of ca—
There's someone right in front of me!
（霊幻）
目の前に 誰かいる！
Who are you?!
何者だ！ 悪霊か？
An evil spirit?!
Boss
Oh, it's just a heel wrestler.
何だ 悪役レスラーか
悪霊かと思ってビックリしただろ！
Don't scare me like that!
I thought you were an evil spirit.
You shouldn't be practicing here.
こんな所で練習してんじゃねえよ！
Uh, Master.
（モブ）
師匠 そっちの方に
悪霊のボスっぽいヤツがいるんで
The boss of sorts of the
evil spirits is over there,
so watch out.
注意したほうがいいですよ～
（霊幻）
えっ…
Evil Spirit:
Boss
Hmph, so you're the boss monkey
of the evil spirits!
ふん！ 悪霊のボスザルが！
プロレスラーのフリをしようが
この霊幻の目は ごまかせんぞ～！
You may have tried to disguise yourself
as a wrestler, but you can't fool me!
（総長(そうちょう)）
え…
I...
俺は～ このトンネル内に～
This tunnel...
When my biker gang and I
were going down this tunnel,
集団バイクで走行中に
the guy in front happened
to slip on a banana peel,
先頭が
バナナの皮を踏んだばっかりに
and we all died! And I'm their leader!
全滅した暴走族の頭～！
This tunnel is...
このトンネルは～
my turf!
俺の縄張り… だあ～！
I'll crush every last intruder!
侵入者は残らず ぶっ潰すぜ！
いくぜ～！
Here we go!
Curse ya!
裏滅死(うらめし)ＹＡ(や)～
Curse ya
Cigarette Burn Poltergeist!
根性焼き ポルターガイスト～！
Wh-What?
なっ なに？
俺の発火攻撃が効かないだと～？
My ignition attack isn't working?
There's a powerful forcefield?
強力なバリアが張られている！
こんなヤツのどこに これほどの…
How could this power be coming
from someone like him?
Crap! I mistook him for a wimp!
マズい～！
一見して雑魚と見誤った！
Too late for regrets now!
（霊幻）
後悔 先に立たず！
The moment that you tried to take on
the genius psychic, Reigen Arataka,
天才能力者
この霊幻新隆と対峙(たいじ)した瞬間
your fate was sealed!
既に決まっていたのさ
You're going to be exorcised!
てめえの成仏はな～！
Banishing Salt Punch!
盛り塩パンチ！
This is one of Reigen's special attacks,
（ナレーション）
食塩をまぶした拳で ぶん殴る
霊幻の必殺技である！
Banishing Salt Punch
where he punches the enemy with
his fist covered in table salt.
あああ～！
あれ？ 全然 大したことねえぞ
Huh? That didn't hurt at all.
Oh, dear.
あら？
So you are a fake...
（総長）
やっぱり お前は偽者…
うぉおお！ ぎゃああああ…
I'm disappearing!
（霊幻）オゾン層に帰るがいい
（総長）待ってくれ！
Go back to the ozone layer.
W-Wait! Wait!
We were just being forced to do this!
俺たちは やらされてただけだ…
ああ～！
あ…
あっ… おい 何やってる？ モブ
早く溶かせ！
Hey, what are you doing, Mob?
Hurry up and melt him.
まあまあ 師匠
ちょっと 話を聞きましょうよ
Now, now, Master.
Let's hear him out.
この奥には—
We're nothing compared to
the evil spirit down the tunnel.
俺たちなんかとは比べ物にならない
邪悪な悪霊が住み着いてる
We've been getting orders from him,
俺たちは そいつに命令されて
and that's why we've been scaring
people that come through.
ここに来たヤツらを
脅かしてただけなんだ
Hmph. Don't think that you can
fool Reigen with such lies!
ふん！ そんなデマカセで
この霊幻をごまかせると思うなよ？
They aren't lies!
デマカセなんかじゃ…
ただ このまま
ぬれぎぬ着せられたまま消されちゃ
It's just that if I disappeared
while being falsely accused,
Death Specters
Gang
I didn't think that we,
the Death Specters,
俺たち“死(デス)・須滅苦侘悪(スペクター)”が
浮かばれねえと思っただけだ
Boss
and our memories could rest in peace!
俺とあいつらの思い出がな
That's all I wanted to say!
言いたいことは それだけだ！
Now you can make me disappear,
melt, or whatever you want!
あとは 消すなり溶かすなり
好きにしやがれ！
So you're trying to make us pity you?
そうやって
同情を買おうってわけか？
ダマされんなよ モブ
これは 典型的な詐欺師の手口だ
Don't let him fool you, Mob!
Those are the typical lies of a con artist.
Melt him.
溶かせ！
Before that, I'm going to go have a look.
その前に ちょっと見てきます
はっ？
Huh?
I thought it was a little weird that the aura
（モブ）
実は 入る前に感じた霊気が
消えてないので
I felt before coming in here
hadn't disappeared yet.
おかしいなとは思ってたんですよ
Well, yeah, me, too...
（霊幻）まあ… 当然 俺も…
（総長）止めろ！
Stop him!
あのガキが いくら強くても
あいつには かなわねえ！
No matter how strong that kid may be,
he doesn't stand a chance.
That thing is an evil spirit that's lived
on this mountain for hundreds of years.
（総長）
あいつは何百年も前から
この山に住み着いてる悪霊だ
Everyone that's died here was killed by him!
ここで死んだヤツらも
全部 そいつに殺されたんだ～！
S-So you guys were also...
じゃ… じゃあ
お前らも そいつに？
No. We just happened to
slip on a banana peel.
いや 俺たちは
バナナの皮を踏んだだけだ～
わあ～！ ぐふっ…
You get it now, don't you?
分かっただろ？
あのガキが かわいいなら
すぐに呼び戻せ！ 早く！
If you care for that kid at all,
call him back.
Hurry!
あっ… おい！ モブ 戻れ！
戻ってこい モブ！
H-Hey, Mob! Come back!
Come back! Mob!
（総長）
ううう…
（悪霊の雄たけび）
（総長）
ひいいい～！
（霊幻）
うっ モブ…
Mob?
Ah.
（モブ）
あっ…
（霊幻）
ん～？
Oh, you're safe.
おっ！ 無事だったか
Yes. That evil spirit wasn't very powerful.
（モブ）
ああ…
大した悪霊でもなかったですし
あああ… お前 何者なんだ？
Wh-Who are you?
Huh? I'm nobody...
（モブ）
えっ？ いや 何者って…
You idiot!
バカ野郎！
You're Mob, the student...
お前は霊能界の新星…
of Reigen Arataka, the new star
of the paranormal world!
この霊幻新隆の弟子
モブだろうが！
Oh, right.
あっ そうでしたね
ハハハ 礼を言うぜ！
I thank you.
これで俺たちも
心おきなく 成仏できるってもんだ
Now we can all pass on peacefully.
Ah, could this be...
（モブ）
あっ… これ もしかして？
（総長）
うわ～！
Death Specters
Gang
Here we go, Boss!
（ヤンキー）
総長 いきますよ？
Yeah!
（総長）
おう！
Death Specters
Gang
グスッ… ありがとよ～
Thanks...
Self-Proclaimed Psychic: Reigen Arataka
~And Mob~
Thanks, dude.
（ヤンキーたち）
ありがとよ
Now we can depart to the afterlife!
これで あの世に行って
復活できるぜ～
Full speed ahead to the next world!
Mob.
（霊幻）モブ
（モブ）あっ…
何してんだ？ 行くぞ！
What are you doing?
Let's go.
Right.
はい
Bus Schedule
（霊幻）
ん？
（モブ）
ところで 師匠…
By the way, Master...
（霊幻）
あ？
Huh?
Why didn't you do anything?
（モブ）
なんで 何も
しなかったんですか？
ええっ！
Well, uh, you know...
あっ いや それはだな…
A-Ahem...
最初に伝えたろ？
Didn't I tell you right at the start
that I'd leave the small fry to you?
“雑魚は任せる”ってよ
Oh, right.
ああ… なるほど～
（霊幻）
フウ…
Seasoning Station
What do you wanna do?
（男子生徒たち）
じゃ どうする？
何か食ってこうぜ～
Let's get something to eat.
I'm not gonna last until I get home.
I know, right?
Sorry to keep you waiting, Mob.
待たせたな モブ
行くか？
Shall we?
はい
Yes.
Does ramen work for you?
（霊幻）
ラーメンで いいか？
（モブ）
はい
Yes.
If you're going to add on
chashu pork, limit it to two.
（霊幻）
チャーシュー追加すんなら
２枚までにしておけよ
All right.
（モブ）
分かりました
～
Here you go.
（店主）
へい お待ち！
～
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 25%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 26%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 27%
A group of telepathics suddenly appear
and disturb Mob's daily life.
（霊幻）
突如として現れた
モブの日常を乱す 脳みそ電波集団
Having doubts about his peaceful youth,
Mob heads into a world of women.
平穏な青い春に疑問を抱いたモブは
女の園へと向かう
Where is the goal?
Which way is tomorrow?
ゴールは どこだ？
明日は どっちだ？
次回「モブサイコ100」
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Episode 2:
第２話
“青い春の疑問　脳感電波部登場”
"Doubts About Youth
~The Telepathy Club Appears~."
Doubts About Youth
~The Telepathy Club Appears~
リアタイ？ 正しい判断です！
Watching it in real time? Wise decision.